(机密报告 主题:导致浣熊市意外的事件)
在21世纪初叶 保护伞公司
At the beginning of the 21st century, the Umbrella Corporation
成为了美国最大的营利性组织
had become the largest commercial entity in the United States.
每10个家庭中就有9个在使用他们生产的产品
Nine out of every ten homes contain its products.
它在政治和经济上的触手伸及各个角落
Its political and financial influence is felt everywhere.
对外而言它是世界上头号的
In public, it is the world's leading supplier
电脑设备 医疗及保健品供应商
of computer technology, medical products and health care.
但即使是它的许多雇员都不知道
Unknown even to its own employees
它主要的利润来源于军火
its massive profits are generated by military technology
基因试验以及生化武器
genetic experimentation and viral weaponry.
《生化危机》
所有保护伞员工任何时刻均须佩挂识别证
All Umbrella staff must wear their identity tags at all times.
所有的放射物将于今天下午5点收集起来
All radiation badges will be collected at 5:00 p.m. this afternoon.
谢谢了! 上帝!
Thank you! God!
别人弄的
Some people.
是
Yeah.
- 别给我看这本书 - 为什么?
- Don't show this to me. - Why not?
因为我很忙
Because I'm busy.
没什么 火警演习
It's nothing. Fire drill.
- 怎么回事? - 火警演习
- What is that? - Fire drill.
- 靠! - 嘿 到底怎么回事?
- Shit! - Hey, what the hell is going on?
- 把电脑都盖起来! 把它拿开! - 他妈的 我正在干!
- Get the computers covered! Move it! - Damn it, I'm trying!
试验设备! 把它们拿开!
The experiments! Move them!
门打不开吗?
Shouldn't the doors open or something?
电梯应该会把我们带到最近的楼层
It's supposed to take us to the nearest floor.
怎么回事?
What's happening?
电话接不通
Line's dead.
- 出什么问题了? - 门开不开了
- What's the problem? - The doors won't open.
- 后面那个门呢? - 也锁住了
- What about the ones at the back? - Locked as well.
这里没有火灾! 没有火灾!
There's no fire here! No fire!
- 密码失效了! - 没有火灾!
- The code doesn't work! - No fire!
- 你们怎么了? - 门打不开!
- What's wrong with you? - The door won't open!
而且水没有地方漏出去
And this water isn't going anywhere.
- 什么? - 这房间是密封的
- What? - It's a sealed room.
- 帮我开门! - 哦 该死的门!
- Help me with the door! - Oh, fuck the doors!
我们必须从这出去 到底怎么了?
We have to get out of here. What's going on?
这种情况以前发生过吗? 我们必须从这出去
Has this happened before? We have to get out of here.
- 我们必须从这出去! - 别紧张
- We have to get out of here! - Take it easy.
- 你别紧张! - 安静!
- You take it easy! - Quiet!
那是什么?
What is that?
哦 上帝啊
Oh, my God.
毒气!
Halon!
停下!
Stop it!
停下! 停!
Stop it! Stop!
救命!
Help!
让我看看
Let me see.
我们一定要从这出去 跑出这幢大楼!
We're going to have to get out of here. We have to get out of this building!
这儿 帮我一把
Here, give me a hand.
这已经是最宽了 门卡住了
That's as far as they'll go. They're caught on something.
够宽了 我能钻过去 然后找人帮忙
That's wide enough. I can squeeze through. I'll get help.
我卡住了 用力推
I'm stuck. You're gonna have to push.
就这样
That's it.
再往外一点
A bit more.
那是什么声音?
What was that?
哦 上帝! 那是闸门的声音! 快出去!
Oh, Christ! It's the brakes! Get out!
- 我动不了了! - 我们必须从这出去!
- I can't move! - We have to get out of here!
把她推出去!
Push her out of the way!
把我拉进去!
Pull me back inside!
有人吗?
Hello?
- 你是谁? - 快走!
- Who are you? - Move!
别碰我! 停下!
Don't touch me! Stop!
- 离我远点! - 趴下!
- Get away from me! - Down!
你在干什么? 我是个警察!
What are you doing? I'm a cop!
我告诉过你 我是警察!
I told you, I'm a cop!
你要把我的手扭断了!
You're breaking my arm!
报告
Report.
快报告
Report now.
什么?
What?
我叫你报告 士兵
I want your report, soldier.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
长官 房子内的主防御系统已经被启动了
Sir, the house's primary defenses have been activated.
她可能还在副作用的影响之下
She's probably still suffering the side effects.
你们想干什么?
What are you doing with us?
那个警察怎么样?
What about the cop?
马修·艾迪生 找不到匹配档案
Matthew Addison. I'm not getting a match.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我刚调来 他们可能还没建档
I just transferred. They probably don't even have me on file yet.
本地警局缺人手 是有这可能
The locals are inefficient. It's possible.
要把他关在这吗?
Should I secure him here?
不 我们把他带走
No. We take him with us.
你不能这样做!
You can't do this!
跟着我!
Blow me.
准备进入蜂巢
Prep for entry to the Hive.
电力断了
Power's down.
- 那就修好它 - 我来修
- So fix it. - I'm on it.
你弄完了吗?
Are you done yet?
你太神经质啦
Jumpy.
准备就绪!
Stand clear!
- 你们有问题吗? - 那个门怎么了?
- You got a problem? - How's that door?
- 被封死了 - 让我来
- It's sealed shut. - Let me.
我神经质?
Jumpy?
躺着别动 躺着别动!
Lie still. Lie still!
看手电筒 眼睛跟着它转
Watch this light. Follow it.
- 现在告诉我这是几根手指? - 三根
- Now, how many fingers am I holding up? - Three.
好
Good.
现在告诉我你叫什么
Now tell me your name.
我不知道
I don't know.
他没事 只是失忆了 就像那一位
He's fine. Memory loss, just like the other one.
让我们把门打开
Let's open that door.
听我说 我想知道你们是谁
Listen to me. I want to know who you people are
你们在干什么
and I want to know what's going on here.
马上!
Now!
我们受雇于同一个老板
You and I have the same employer.
我们都替保护伞公司干活
We all work for the Umbrella Corporation.
我们头上的大楼是蜂巢的紧急入口
The mansion above us is an emergency entrance to the Hive.
你是安排在那里保护入口的安全人员
You are security operatives placed there to protect that entrance.
那这个呢?
What about this?
你结婚是假的
Your marriage is a fake.
只是你伪装的一部分 以保持蜂巢的隐秘
Just part of your cover to protect the secrecy of the Hive.
那什么是蜂巢?
And what is the Hive?
给他们看
Show them.
正在读取蜂巢的展示图
Accessing schematic of the Hive.
浣熊市 最近的市镇
Raccoon City, nearest urban center.
这是我们发现你的那幢大楼
The mansion where we found you
从那里我们进入了火车
and through which we gained access to the train
火车又带我们来到蜂巢
which, in turn, brought us to the Hive.
蜂巢位于地下
The Hive itself is located underground
在浣熊市地底深处
deep beneath the streets of Raccoon City.
这是一个绝密的研究机构
A top-secret research facility
由保护伞组织所有并运营
owned and operated by the Umbrella Corporation.
蜂巢内共有超过500名技术人员 科学家和后勤人员
The Hive houses over 500 technicians, scientists and support staff.
他们在地下工作和生活
They live and work underground.
他们的研究至关重要
Their research is of the highest importance.
但工作性质是保密的
Its nature is classified.
我们在地图上的位置由热感应点标出
Our position on the map is indicated by heat signature.
为什么我什么事都想不起来了?
Why can't I remember anything?
蜂巢有自己的防御机制
The Hive has its own defense mechanisms
都由电脑操控
all computer-controlled.
一种神经毒气被排放到了大楼
A nerve gas was released into the house.
毒气的主要作用是
Primary effect of the gas
使吸入者完全昏迷4小时
complete unconsciousness lasting anything up to four hours.
其副作用是不定的 但是可能导致失忆
Secondary effects are varied, but can include acute memory loss.
- 持续多久? - 每个人都不一样
- For how long? - Subjective.
可能是一小时 一天或者一个星期
An hour, day, week.
所以你是说这个地方遭到了攻击?
So you're saying this place was attacked?
恐怕状况还要更麻烦
I'm afraid things are a little more complicated than that.
长官! 我们已经打通去蜂巢的通道了
Sir! We've breached the Hive.
J.D.
到了
Got it.
毒气已经散了
Halon content has dissipated.
这是用来改善地下工作环境的 就当成是地上的景象
Makes it easier to work underground, thinking there's a view.
看来我们要走楼梯了
Looks like we're taking the stairs.
- 报告情况 - 红皇后已锁定了我们
- Status. - Red Queen is locked onto us.
她知道我们在这里
She knows that we're here.
红皇后是谁?
Who's the Red Queen?
世界上最好的人工智能系统
State-of-the-art a rtificial intelligence.
她就是控制蜂巢的电脑
She is the computer that controls the Hive.
这会拖慢我们的速度
This is gonna slow us down.
我们去皇后那儿的路上要经过这些实验室
Our route to the Queen takes us straight through these labs.
雷恩 JD 去看看淹成什么样了
Rain, J.D., see how bad the flooding is.
卡普兰 去找一条别的路
Kaplan, find us an alternate route.
这里出什么事了?
What happened here?
5小时前 红皇后突然开始杀人
Five hours ago, Red Queen went homicidal.
她把蜂巢封锁起来后杀了里面所有的人
Sealed the Hive and killed everyone down here.
- 天呐 - 当我们发现这里的状况后
- Jesus. - When we realized what was happening
我的小队就被派到这里来关掉她
my team was dispatched to shut her down.
她为什么要这么做?
Why did she do it?
这我们也不知道
That we don't know.
有可能是受到了外部操纵
But outside interference is a possibility.
上帝!
Jesus!
嘿 你还好吗?
Hey. You okay?
- 给你 - 不
- Here. - No.
- 我还好 - 拜托 穿上吧
- I'm fine. - Please, come on.
这里很冷的
It's cold in here.
你是
Are you
你还记得以前的事吗?
Do you remember anything from before this?
不 火车上之前的事什么都记不得了
No. Nothing before the train.
你呢?
And you?
不 什么都记不得
No. Nothing.
我找到了另一条路 但要花不少时间
I found an alternate route, but it's gonna cost us time.
我们绕回去 穿过B餐厅
We double back, cut through Dining Hall B
然后从这里直达目的地
then we're right on track.
长官 没路了 整层都被淹了
Sir, no go. The whole level's flooded.
好吧 我们的进度已经落后了
All right, we're behind schedule.
所以行动起来
So let's move it.
来吧
Come on.
可怜的混蛋
Poor bastards.
B餐厅
Dining Hall B.
地图上是这么说的
That's what it says on the map.
也许你看错了
Maybe you're reading it wrong.
也许公司在这里藏了一些秘密
Maybe the corporation's keeping a few secrets down here.
一些你不该看的东西
Something you're not supposed to see.
JD 你和雷恩看着犯人然后守住出口
J.D., you and Rain keep the prisoner here and secure the exit.
长官 这件房间的毒气显示为零
Sir, halon levels are nonexistent in this room.
我想系统失灵了
I think the system malfunctioned.
好 可能还有幸存者
All right. There may be survivors.
搜索一下 但别散了
Give me a search line, but keep it tight.
走吧
Move it.
- 我说了别散了 - 对不起
- I said keep it tight. - Sorry.
我不太确定我还能不能回忆起这下面的事情
I'm not sure I want to remember what went on down here.
这不怪你
I don't blame you.
他们在这里面保存了什么?
What do they keep in these things?
我怎么会知道?
How do I know?
怎么用了那么久?
What's taking so long?
红皇后的防御系统十分完备 我们要完成任务很困难
Red Queen's defenses are in place. She's making it difficult.
先别弄了
Let's pack it up.
你待在这
You stay here.
自动感应灯 没什么可担心的
The lights are automated. Nothing to worry about.
- 传输器就位 - 收到
- Transmitter in position. - Roger.
正在解码
Running the bypass.
将
Checkmate.
行动
Move up.
- 那是什么东西? - 那是我们关闭皇后用的东西
- What is that? - That's what will shut the Queen down.
它能放出一道强大的电流
Delivers a massive electrical charge.
扰乱主机并迫使它重启
Scrambles the mainframe and forces it to reboot.
某种休眠状态防卫机制
Some kind of dormant defense mechanism.
- 打开门就会启动它 - 让它继续休眠
- Opening the door tripped it. - Put it back to sleep.
我正在处理
Working on it.
- 你能把门打开吗? - 我正在试
- Would you open that door now, please? - I'm trying.
待在自己的位置 大家都冷静下来
Hold your positions. Everyone stay calm.
那是什么?
What's that?
- 卡普兰 快! - 我们得让他们从里边出来!
- Kaplan, quick! - We gotta get them out of there!
- 卡普兰 你得快点! - 快啊!
- Kaplan, you've gotta hurry! - Come on!
趴下! 快趴下!
Down! Get down!
- 当心! 某种东西正在杀死他们! - 天呐! 快点啊
- Look out! Something's killing them! - Jesus! Come on, man.
别对我那样!
Don't do this to me!
医务兵! 医务兵!
Medic! Medic!
- 快打开门! - 快打开这道门!
- Open the door! - Open this door!
- 我正在试 - 保持清醒
- I am trying. - Stay conscious.
你会休克的 保持清醒!
You're going into shock. Stay awake!
- 我快完成了 - 长官! 它又回来了!
- I am almost there. - Sir! It's coming back!
- 打开门! - 我正在试!
- Open the door! - I'm trying!
那就再努力点儿!
Well, try harder!
它又回来了!
It's coming back!
噢 我的天!
Oh, God!
- 就那么做! - 我快完成了
- Just do it! - I'm almost there.
快些!
Come on!
- 混蛋! - 好了
- Shit! - Got it.
好吧
All right.
我们继续
Let's do it.
干什么?
Do what?
我们得完成任务
We have to complete the mission.
我才不去那种鬼地方
There is no way I'm going down there.
她的防御系统已经关了
Her defenses are down.
之前也是这样 不是吗?
Déjà vu, anyone?
继续前进
Keep going.
帮我一把
Give me a hand.
出去! 出去! 你们不能进来
Get out! Get out! You can't be in here.
别相信她说的任何话
Don't listen to anything she says.
她是红皇后的全息影像
She's a holographic representation of the Red Queen.
你们必须出去!
You have to get out!
是模仿首席程序师的女儿做的
Modeled after the head programmer's daughter.
她会欺骗我们 迷惑我们
She'll try to deceive us, confuse us.
我不建议你们这样做 关闭我会导致主电源断电
I wouldn't advise this. Disabling me will result in loss of primary power.
她会想尽一切办法来阻止我们关了她
She'll say anything to stop us from shutting her down.
我恳求你们
I implore you.
- 请你让开吧 - 求求你们
- Implore away. - Please?
求求你们
Please?
你们都会死在这里的
You're all going to die down here.
这个脉冲能迫使断路器切断她的主机30秒
That pulse forces the circuit breaker to shut down her mainframe for 30 seconds.
在这之后 如果我没有找到她的主板 她就会重启
After that, if I don't have her board, she can reboot.
他们迟到了
They're late.
我去看看
I'm on it.
JD 发现一个幸存者!
J.D., we got a survivor!
没事了 我们是来帮助你们的.
It's okay. We're here to help.
你好像伤得很重
You seem to be in some serious
别靠近我! 别靠近我!
Get off of me! Get off of me!
JD 在我发火前最好让她离开!
J.D., get her off of me before I stab her ass!
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
她咬我了 她从我这儿咬去了一大块肉
She bit me, man. She took a chunk clean right out of me.
趴下
Stay down.
我在警告你 趴下!
I'm warning you, stay down!
她疯了
She's crazy.
再往前一步 我就开枪了
Come any closer, and I'll fire.
我是认真的!
I mean it!
去死吧
Damn you.
我打了她5枪 她怎么还能站着?
I shot her five times. How was she still standing?
贱逼现在没法站着了
Bitch isn't standing now.
- 枪声是怎么回事? - 我们发现了一个幸存者
- What was all the shooting? - We found a survivor.
- 你向他开了枪? - 她疯了 她居然咬我
- And you shot him? - She was crazed. She bit me.
她不见了 她不见了!
She's gone. She's gone!
胡说八道!
That's bullshit!
她就倒在那 但她现在不见了!
She fell right here, but she's gone!
看 看这个
Look, look at this.
这里有血 但不多
There's blood, but it's not much.
看上去已经凝结了
Looks like it's coagulated.
- 是的 - 那不可能
- Yeah. - It's not possible.
为什么?
Why not?
因为只有死后血才会这样
Because blood doesn't do that till after you're dead.
我们可以走了吗?
Can we go now?
在其他组员过来之前 我们哪儿也不去
We're not going anywhere till the rest of the team get here.
- 没人会来了 - 你他妈说什么?
- There's no one else coming. - What the fuck are you talking about?
等一下
Wait.
安静
Quiet.
妈的!
Fuck!
别再过来了! 他们在我们后面
Don't come any closer! They're behind us.
上帝啊!
Jesus!
他们到处都是
They're everywhere.
伙计们 他们到处都是 他们把我们包围了
Guys, they're everywhere. They're all around us.
我说过了给我退后!
I said stay back!
他们怎么打不死?
Why aren't they dying?
当心那些培养槽! 培养槽!
Watch the tank! The tank!
- 我们走吧! - 快点!
- Let's go! - Hurry up!
- 等等! - 快 我们走吧!
- Wait! - Come on, let's go!
- 快点啊! - 别停! 快!
- Move! - Keep moving! Come on!
走!
Move!
我可以帮你拿到病毒
I can help you get the virus.
我能搞到安全密码 监控图 还有计划
I have access to security codes, surveillance plans, the works.
妈的!
Shit!
- 我们跟其他人走散了! - 继续走!
- We lost the others! - Keep moving!
- 你在等吗? - 不知道密码
- You waited? - Didn't know the code.
快 快
Come on, come on.
- 妈的! - 快
- Shit! - Come on.
- 快 - 快点
- Come on. - Hurry up.
- 快点伙计 - 见鬼!
- Come on, man. - Shit!
- 怎么用了这么久? - 我正在试!
- What's taking so long? - I'm trying!
快
Come on.
- 起开! 密码是什么? - 赶快!
- Move! What's the code? - Hurry up!
我子弹快打光了!
I'm running out of ammo!
0 4 3 2 不 5!
Zero, four, three, two. No, five!
- 什么? - 0 4 3…
- What? - Zero, four, three...
- 密码是什么? - 0 4…
- What is the code? - Zero, four...
…0 3 1…
...zero, three, one...
…9 6 5
nine, six, five.
- 搞定了? - 看 这多简单
- Got it? - See how easy that was?
- 靠! - J.D. 不!
- Shit! - J.D., no!
抓住我的手 伙计! 快!
Grab my hand, man! Come on!
别放手!
Don't let go!
- J.D.! - 雷恩!
- J.D.! - Rain!
尸体到哪去了? 它们去哪儿了?
Where are the bodies? Where did they go?
操!
Fuck!
不管它们是什么 外面那些都太多了
Whatever they are, there's too many of them out there.
他们是什么还用问吗?
Whatever they are? It's pretty obvious what they are.
实验服 徽章 这些人之前就在这里工作!
Lab coats, badges. Those people used to work here!
所有在这里工作的人都死了
All the people working here are dead.
那也没能阻止它们到处游荡
Well, that isn't stopping them from walking around.
它们是从哪来的? 为什么进来的时候没看到它们?
Well, where did they come from? Why didn't we see them on the way in?
当你切断电源的时候 门都打开了
When you cut the power, you unlocked the doors.
是你让它们出来的
You let them out.
我们永远到不了地面了
We're never gonna make it to the surface.
你是安全人员
You are security operatives.
安排在那里保护入口的安全人员
Security operatives placed there to protect that entrance.
我的枪上了子弹 还剩一个弹夹
I've got one in the breech and an extra mag.
丽莎?
Lisa?
我可以帮你拿到病毒
I can help you get the virus.
我能搞到安全密码 监控图 还有计划
I have access to security codes, surveillance plans, the works.
但是?
But?
- 但是需要一些价码 - 说吧
- But there's gonna be a price. - Name it.
- 她是谁? - 我妹妹
- Who was she? - My sister.
像保护伞这样的公司以为他们凌驾于法律之上
Corporations like Umbrella think they're above the law.
但不是这样的
But they're not.
我们有千千万万的人有着同样的想法
There are hundreds of thousands of us who think the same
遍及全世界
all over the world.
一些人提供情报
Some of us provide information
其他的给予支援
others give their support.
一些人直接采取行动
Some take more direct action.
比如你
Like you.
如果你的朋友们再细心一点的话
If your friends had been a little more thorough
他们就能识破我的假ID了
they would've seen right through my false ID.
那么所有警报都会被拉响
Then all the red flags would've gone off
匡蒂科 国安局 FBI暴力犯罪逮捕项目 还有其他这些
Quantico, NSA, ViCAP, all the rest.
我没有办法混入蜂巢
There's no way I could've infiltrated the Hive.
所以你让你妹妹来
So you sent your sister.
我们需要一些确凿的证据
We needed something concrete.
能把保护伞曝光给媒体的东西
Anything to expose Umbrella to the press.
关于地下研究的证据
Proof of the research that was going on down here.
什么样的研究?
What kind of research?
非法的那种
The illegal kind.
基因研究
Genetic.
病毒研究
Viral.
我妹妹想偷带出去一份
My sister was going to smuggle out
他们正在研发的病毒样本
a sample of the virus they were developing.
那她到底要怎么带出去?
So how was she going to make it out of here?
她在蜂巢里有一个内线 我从来没见过
She had a contact within the Hive, someone I never met.
他们能弄到保安密码 监控 她需要的一切
They had access to security codes, surveillance, everything she needed.
那她为什么失败了?
So why didn't she make it?
可能她信错人了
Maybe she trusted the wrong person.
可能他们给她下了个套
Maybe they set her up.
把病毒据为己有了
Kept the virus for themselves.
你知道在黑市上T病毒值多少钱吗?
Do you know how much the T-virus would be worth on the open market?
- 什么 不惜以这样的代价? - 是的
- What, worth all this? - Yeah.
对某些人来说是的
To someone.
别开枪! 别开枪!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
- 关上门! - 它们就在后面!
- Close that door! - They're right behind us!
放开! 放开!
Get off!. Get off!.
不要!
Stop it!
狗娘养的!
Son of a bitch!
- 你还好吧? - 嗯
- You okay? - Yeah.
就在我们后面 那这扇门呢?
Right behind us. What about this door?
- 它们就在外面等着呢 - 那条路呢?
- They're waiting out there too. - And that way?
这是死路 皇后的主机房没有出口
It's a dead end. There's no way out of the Queen's chamber.
那我们就等
So we wait.
如果收不到你的消息 他们一定会派支援什么过来的
If someone doesn't hear from you, they'll send backup or something.
对吗?
Right?
怎么? 有什么问题吗?
What? What's wrong?
我们没有时间了
We don't have much time.
你记得我们从大楼来这的路上
You know those blast doors we passed
经过的那些防爆门吗?
on the way in from the mansion?
它们在一小时内就要被锁死了
They seal shut in just under an hour.
如果我们那时候还没出去 就出不去了
If we're not out of here by then, we're not getting out.
你在说什么? 他们不能把我们就活埋在这啊
What are you talking about? They can't just bury us alive down here.
这是唯一的保险措施
Containing the incident is the only fail-safe plan they had
为了防止任何泄露
against possible contamination.
而你到现在 我们被困在他妈地下半英里深的地方的时候
And you're only telling us this now, when we're trapped
才告诉我们这些?
half a fucking mile underground?
我们必须找到一条路离开这个房间
We have to find a way out of this room.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
- 你要拿那些东西去哪? - 我要重启她
- Where are you taking those? - I'm turning her back on.
- 这不是个好主意 - 她知道怎么离开这里
- That is not a good idea. - She'll know a way out of here.
那疯子杀了我的队友
That homicidal bitch killed my team.
那疯子可能是我们离开这儿的唯一方法
That homicidal bitch may be our only way out of here.
想想她受到的这些待遇 我确定她会非常乐意帮我们的
Considering the way she's being treated, I'm sure she'll be real happy to help us out.
你之前说的那个断路器
That circuit breaker you were talking about.
- 你能解开它吗? - 可以
- Can you bypass it? - Yeah.
那就动手
So do it.
搞定 断路器终止了
All right, circuit breaker is disabled.
如果这次我再按下这个开关 她就不会被关闭了
This time if I hit the switch, she won't be able to shut down.
她会被烧焦
She's gonna fry.
卡普兰?
Kaplan?
肯定是启动电压把电路板烧坏了
The initial charge must have damaged her boards.
啊 原来你们在这
Ah, there you are.
我收集的东西已经失控了
Things, I gather, have gone out of control.
快把那他妈的开关给我 我要把你屁股给烧了
Give me that fucking switch right now. I'm gonna fry your ass.
我警告过你了 不是吗?
I did warn you, didn't I?
告诉我们下面发生什么
Tell us what's going on down here.
研究和开发
Research and development.
那T病毒是什么?
What about the T-virus?
T病毒是医药科学上的一大突破
The T-virus was a major medical breakthrough
不过它也具有极为有利可图的军事价值
although it clearly also possessed highly profitable military applications.
那这又跟外面那些东西有什么关系呢?
How does it explain those things out there?
就算在死亡状态下 人体也能保持活性
Even in death, the human body still remains active.
头发跟指甲会继续生长
Hair and fingernails continue to grow.
新细胞会产生
New cells are produced
而大脑本身也还保持着微弱的电流
and the brain itself holds a small electrical charge
直到几个月后才消失.
that takes months to dissipate.
T病毒不论是对细胞生长
The T-virus provides a massive jolt
还是对微弱电流脉冲
both to cellular growth
都会产生巨大的冲击
and to those trace electrical impulses.
简单来说
Put quite simply
它重新激活了人体
it reanimates the body.
死而复生?
It brings the dead back to life?
不完全是
Not fully.
它们只拥有最简单的行动能力
The subjects have the simplest of motor functions.
可能加上少许的记忆 事实上没有任何智能
Perhaps a little memory. Virtually no intelligence.
它们被最基本的神经冲动
They are driven by the basest of impulses
最原始的需求驱动着
the most basic of needs.
什么需求?
Which is?
食欲
The need to feed.
要怎么杀了它们?
How do you kill them?
击断颈椎或者重创大脑
Severing the top of the spinal column or massive trauma to the brain
是最有效的方法
are the most effective methods.
你意思是爆头
You mean shoot them in the head.
为什么你要把这下面的人都杀了?
Why did you kill everybody down here?
T病毒已经侵入了空调通风系统
The T-virus escaped into the air conditioning system
开始了无法控制的传染模式
and an uncontrolled pattern of infection began.
病毒具有很强的变异性
The virus is protean
会由液体传染变为空气传染再到血液传染
changing from liquid to airborne to blood transmission
依环境而定
depending on its environment.
它几乎不可消灭
It's almost impossible to kill.
我不能让它从蜂巢里扩散出来
I couldn't allow it to escape from the Hive
所以我采取了措施
so I took steps.
- 措施 - 你一定要理解
- Steps. - You must understand.
被传染的人 我决不能让你们离开
Those who become infected, I can't allow you to leave.
哗 我们又没被感染
Whoa. We're not infected.
仅仅是那些生物的一次咬伤或抓伤 也足以让你受到感染
Just one bite, one scratch from these creatures is sufficient
然后你会变成它们中的一员
and then you become one of them.
系统检查显示我的主驱动断路器
A check of my systems indicates my main drive circuit breaker
被关掉了
has been disabled.
我能问为什么吗?
May I ask why?
留一手 我们需要离开这的方法
Insurance. We need a way out of here.
假如你拒绝帮忙的话 我们随时可以制服你
If you refuse to help at any time, we flip the switch.
懂了吗?
Understand?
你先走吧
After you.
这是什么鬼地方?
What the hell is this place?
设备管道
The utility tunnels.
它们在蜂巢下面 用来送水 气和电线
They run underneath the Hive for water, gas and power lines.
- 我们来过这里 - 继续走
- It's been in here before. - Keep moving.
- 我们在绕圈吧 - 这就是电脑给我们的路线
- We're going around in circles. - This is the route the computer gave us.
- 你怎么还听她的? - 够了!
- Why are you listening to her? - Enough already!
我们只能不停往前走因为它们就在我们后面
We have no choice but to keep moving 'cause those things are right behind us.
- 那网子根本挡不住他们 - 快走吧
- That mesh isn't gonna hold. - Keep moving.
天啊! 停! 它们太多了!
Jesus Christ! Hold it! There's too many of them!
- 天啊! - 妈的!
- Jesus! - Fuck!
快爬到管子上去 快爬到管子上去!
Up on the pipes. Up on the pipes!
快啊 大家!
Quickly, everyone!
- 走啊! - 走吧! 上面有条路!
- Let's go! - Come on! There's a way up!
小心! 挡住它们!
Watch out! Keep 'em back!
快上去! 快啊!
Go on up! Move it!
妈的 好吧
Shit. Okay.
来这儿! 它们太多了! 来啊! 走 走 走!
Get over here! There's too many of them! Come on! Go, go, go!
走啊!
Go on!
走! 走! 我能应付!
Go! Go! I can manage!
抓住你了!
Gotcha!
雷恩?
Rain?
雷恩
Rain.
干吗?
What?
你的伤口要赶快治疗
We have to do something about your wounds.
我没事
I'm fine.
我说了我没事
I said I'm fine.
哼? 你们很喜欢 对不对? 哈?
Hm? You like that, don't you? Huh?
你们喜欢血的味道 对吧?
You like the way it tastes, don't you?
喜欢那股味道?
Like the taste of that?
她是对的
She was right.
我们全都要死在这下面了
We're all gonna die down here.
不 我们一定可以出去
No. We're getting out.
所有的人
All of us.
卡普兰 还好吧?
Kaplan, are you okay?
噢 天啊!
Oh, God!
支持住!
Hold on!
- 帮帮他 - 我没办法
- Help him. - I can't.
- 你在等什么? - 我瞄不准!
- What are you waiting for? - I can't focus!
我看不见!
I can't see!
- 卡普兰 往上走! - 快上去!
- Kaplan, go up! - Get up there!
你就快到了 继续走!
You almost got it. Keep going!
- 加油! 加油! - 你行的!
- Come on! Come on! - You can do it!
你做到了!
You got it!
- 好了 卡普兰 - 只管待在那!
- Okay, Kaplan. - Just stay there!
坚持住 我们会来接你的
Hold on. We're gonna come get you.
把这线剪了扔给他 然后我们就可以过去接他了
Cut this wire and throw it to him. Then we can go get him.
撑住!
Hold on!
还真走运
That's lucky.
你们走吧
I want you to go.
- 我们不会丢下你的 卡普兰 - 不 你们走
- We're not leaving you, Kaplan. - Yes, you are.
你杀不完它们的
You can't kill all of them.
那我也逃不了了
And I'm not going anywhere.
你们走吧 快!
I want you to go. Now!
拜托
Please.
只管走
Just do it.
只管快点走!
Just do it now!
拜托
Please.
走!
Go!
我可不会这么简单就给你们吃的!
You're gonna have to work for your meal!
来吧
Come on.
把手给我 放我肩膀上
Give me your arm. Up over my shoulder.
准备好了? 来吧
Ready? There we go.
等我离开这之后
When I get out of here
我想我要去打个炮
I think I'm gonna get laid.
嗯 你可能还想先洗个澡
Yeah. You might want to clean up a little bit first.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait.
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
蓝色是病毒 绿色是抗体
Blue for the virus. Green for the antivirus.
- 有解药的 - 你说什么?
- There's a cure. - What are you talking about?
有解药的
There's a cure.
这个过程是可逆的
The process can be reversed.
有解药的!
There's a cure!
你会好起来的!
You're gonna be okay!
我刚刚还开始担心了呢
I was beginning to worry.
T病毒就是存放在这的
This is where they kept the T-virus.
你怎么会知道这么多?
How do you know all this?
因为我本来想偷走它
Because I was gonna steal it.
我就是你妹妹的内线
I was your sister's contact.
- 你背叛了她 - 我不知道
- You betrayed her. - I don't know.
- 整件事都是因为你 - 我记不起来了
- You caused all of this. - I can't remember.
告诉我事实
The truth.
我已经不记得事实了
I don't remember the truth.
我就不明白了!
I don't understand!
它不见了
It's gone.
它不在这里
It's not there.
撑不住了
I can't.
我已经撑不住了
I just can't.
快完了
It's over.
我可以帮你拿到病毒
I can help you get the virus.
我能搞到安全密码 监控图 还有计划
I have access to security codes, surveillance plans, the works.
但是需要一些价码
But there's gonna be a price.
说吧
Name it.
向我保证你会把这组织给摧毁了
You have to guarantee me that you will bring this corporation down.
斯宾塞? 斯宾塞?
Spence? Spence?
谢谢
Thank you.
斯宾塞?
Spence?
我们还是有办法离开这儿的 跟我来吧
We can still make it out of here. Come with me.
我们将可以拥有我们想要的一切
We can have everything we've ever wanted.
大把钞票在外面等着我们
Money's out there waiting.
你绝对想不到有多少
You wouldn't believe how much.
你以为这样子我的梦想就会实现了吗?
Is that how you thought all my dreams were gonna come true?
拜托
Please.
我不想开枪打死你
I wouldn't want to shoot you.
那些子弹可能还用得着呢
Might need the bullets.
退后
Back off.
我不会拿一分钱的
I won't take any part in this.
好啊 不过你不可能
Okay, but you can't just
这么简单就脱离干系的
wash your hands of this.
我们为同一家公司效力 你知道他们做了些什么
We work for the same company. You knew what they did.
我在试着阻止他们
I was trying to stop them.
你真觉得
You really believe that
像他这种人
people like him
能改变任何事情?
will ever change anything?
不
No
什么都
Nothing
不会改变
ever changes.
解毒血清
Where is
在哪里?
the antivirus?
在你找到我的
It's on the train
那辆火车上
where you found me.
离它绝对没有三尺远
Couldn't have been standing more than three feet from it.
我差点就出去了
I so nearly made it out.
没想到那贱逼电脑居然在蜂巢外面有防卫系统
Didn't realize that bitch of a computer had defense systems outside the Hive.
同意还是拒绝?
In or out?
同意
In
还是拒绝?
or out?
我不知道我们有过什么
I don't know what we had
可现在结束了
but it's over.
给我
Back
他妈的后退
the fuck off.
我已经开始怀念你了
I'm missing you already.
你男朋友还真是个人渣
Your boyfriend's a real asshole.
他把锁给打坏了
He shot the locking mechanism out.
我不敢相信那贱人居然就这么跑了
I can't believe that son of a bitch is gonna get away with this.
我不这么觉得
I don't think so.
我可一向是个坏女孩喔
I've been a bad, bad girl.
噢 我的天
Oh, my God.
那他妈是什么?
What the fuck is that?
蜂巢早期的一个试验品
One of the Hive's early experiments
通过把T病毒直接注入活的细胞组织产生
produced by injecting the T-virus directly into living tissue.
结果很不稳定
The results were unstable.
现在吃掉新的DNA后 它将会突变
Now that it has fed on fresh DNA, it will mutate
变成更强 更快的猎手
becoming a stronger, faster hunter.
真棒
Great.
你知道它逃跑了 为什么不警告我们?
If you knew it was loose, why didn't you warn us?
因为这是她专门留给咱们的
'Cause she was saving it for us.
对不对?
Isn't that right?
我没有想到你们会活到现在
I didn't think any of you would make it this far.
就是没被感染也不可能
Not without infection.
为什么不告诉我们有抗病毒血清?
Why didn't you tell us about the antivirus?
被感染了这么长时间
This long after infection
血清不一定会管用
there's no guarantee it would work.
但是还有机会 对吗?
But there's a chance, right?
我不做有风险的交易
I don't deal in chance.
去你妈的
Fuck it.
没时间了 伙计们
No pressure, guys.
你们需要4位数的密码
You require the four digit access code.
我可以给你们密码 但你们必须先为我做件事
I can give you the code, but first you must do something for me.
- 你想要什么? - 你们中有人被感染了
- What do you want? - One of your group is infected.
我要她的命
I require her life for the code.
抗病毒血清的药就在平台上
The antivirus is right there on the platform.
- 就在那里! - 对不起
- It's right there! - I'm sorry.
这是我无法承担的风险
It's a risk I cannot take.
她说得对
She's right.
那是唯一的办法
It's the only way.
你得杀了我
You're gonna have to kill me.
不
No
要不我们都会死在这里.
Otherwise we all die down here.
玻璃是加固过的
The glass is reinforced
但是不会永远不破
but it won't hold forever.
- 动手吧 - 不
- Do it. - No.
- 起来 - 只管动手
- Get up. - Just do it.
- 雷恩 赶快起来 - 动手!
- Rain, please get up. - Do it!
- 你没多少时间下决定了 - 起来 求你了
- You don't have long to decide. - Get up, please.
- 你没有选择了 - 杀了她
- You have no choice. - Kill her.
现在就杀了她 你没有任何选择余地
Kill her now. You don't have any choice.
- 快点动手! - 我办不到!
- Just do it now! - I can't!
- 求求你 - 动手
- Please. - Do it.
- 杀了她 - 只管动手
- Kill her. - Just do it.
现在就杀了她!
Kill her now!
杀了她!
Kill her!
这婊子不肯开门 所以我只好把她给烧焦了
The bitch wouldn't open the door, so I had to fry her.
走
Move.
那他妈是什么?
What the fuck was that?
说来话长
It's a long story.
启动它
Start it up.
我去拿病毒
I'll get the virus.
我已经开始怀念你了
I'm missing you already.
好 我们上路了
Okay, we're in business.
全速前进
Full power.
我们要走了!
We're leaving!
我不想变成那些玩意中的一个
I don't want to be one of those things
四处游荡没有灵魂
walking around without a soul.
你不会的
You won't.
等时候到了
When the time comes
你来解决
you'll take care of it.
没人会死的
No one else is gonna die.
好吗?
Okay?
给你
Here.
我还没死呢
I'm not dead yet.
我想还是把枪拿回来吧
I think I'll have that back.
我真想亲你一口 小婊砸
I could kiss you, you bitch.
后面出什么事了?
What's going on back there?
- 赶快把我们带出去! - 再快的话 我们就要脱轨了!
- Get us the fuck out of here! - Any faster, we'll come off the rails!
开门!
Open the doors!
快!
Now!
我辜负了所有人
I failed all of them.
我搞砸了
I failed.
听我说
Listen to me.
你已经尽力了
There is nothing else you could've done.
是公司的错 不是你的
The corporation's guilty here, not you.
而且我们终于有了证据
And we finally have the proof.
保护伞公司不可能有办法
That way Umbrella can't get
逃脱干系了
get away with this.
那是什么?
What is it?
你被感染了 但你会没事的
You're infected, but you're gonna be okay.
我不要失去你
I'm not losing you.
救命!
Help!
救救他 你们在干什么?
Help him. What are you doing?
马特!
Matt!
他在突变
He's mutating.
我要让他进入复仇女神项目
I want him in the Nemesis Program.
滚开!
Get off!
这是怎么了?
What's happening?
马特!
Matt!
把她隔离起来
I want her quarantined.
严密观察 并且对血液进行全面检测
Close observation and a full series of blood tests.
看她是不是被感染了
Let's see if she's infected.
把她带到浣熊市的研究所
Take her to the Raccoon City facility.
然后组织一个小队
Then assemble the team.
我们要重新打开蜂巢
We're reopening the Hive.
我想知道下面发生了什么
I want to know what went on down there.
赶快行动
Just do it.
谁在里面?
Who's in there?
让我出去!
Let me out!
谁在里面?
Who's in there?